GRACE YUNANTASSA FIRGIA

Jakarta, Indonesia • +62823-2842-5566 • gracellata@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/grace-firgia/

SUMMARY

An experienced software engineer specializing in website development with great self-management project skills. Have done numerous projects involving front and back-end development. Mastering Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React.js, Next.js Node.js, Nest.js, Laravel and Codelgniter 3 combine with MySQL, PostgreSQL and REST API as daily drivers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, PT Bithealth Teknologi Pintar (Bithealth)

Mar 2023 - Present

- Develop and optimize a *Human Capital Management System (HCMS)* used by over 13,000 users, focusing on improving system performance and user experience.
- Develop and optimize a *Hospital Information System (HIS)* with an integrated *Electronic Medical Record (EMR)*, used by over 5 major hospitals and 100+ clinics, focused on developing high-performance solutions and reusable components to streamline healthcare operations.
- Successfully reduced report generating time from 3 hours to just 2 minutes by re-engineering data handling algorithms and optimizing database queries, leading to significant improvements in operational efficiency.
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs for integration with third-party services, reducing manual processing by 30%.
- Reduced application load times by 25% through performance optimization techniques, leading to a better user experience.
- Conducted code reviews and mentored junior developers, fostering a culture of best practices and continuous improvement.

Stacks:

Typescript, Next.js, Nest.js, React.js, Express.js, Postgresql, Mongodb, TypeORM, Sequelize, Tailwind, RabbitMQ

Fullstack Developer, PT Erakomp Infonusa

Jul 2022 - Mar 2023

- Plan and manage project timelines, reducing delivery times by 30%.
- Managing the complete software development process from conception to deployment.
- Managing the end-to-end life cycle for the production of software and applications.
- Overseeing and guiding the analyzing, writing, building, and deployment of software
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, enhancing project success rates by 10%.

Stacks

Javascript, Nuxt.js, Vue.js, Express.js, Mysql, Sequelize

Fullstack Developer, PT Galactic Multimedia (Oomph)

Mar 2022 - Jul 2022

- Built innovative microservices and Web Services (incl. REST).
- Producing, maintaining, and modifying websites and user interfaces.
- Ensuring websites are accessible across many platforms, including laptops and smartphones.
- Work across functions, collaborate with other engineers, as well as product design and ideation

Stacks:

PHP, Code Igniter 3, Mysql, Sequelize

Software Engineer, Lumbung Nusa

- Aug 2020 Feb 2022
- Team up with the UI/UX designer and bridge the gap between graphical design and technical implementation, taking an active role on both sides and defining how the application looks and works.
- Responsible for translation of the UI/UX design wireframes to actual code that will produce visual elements of the application.
- Developed and maintained web applications for a leading e-commerce platform, focusing on improving user experience and performance.
- Responsible for developing the Lumbung Kurir App, Lumbungnusa's courier application and warehouse system.

Stacks:

Javascript, Vue.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Capacitor

Fullstack Developer, Freelance

2019 - Present

- · Company Profile
- · Petshop Grooming Booking App
- Library Information System
- SPM Rental Motor Website
- EPT Toefl Booking Website using Midtrans payment gateway
- Desa Ranggo Infrastructure Rental Website
- · E-commerce with Midtrans payment gateway

Stacks:

Javascript, Vue.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Flutter 3

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer

Aug 2017 - May 2022

Universitas Teknologi Yogyakarta Informatika - Fakultas Teknologi Informasi dan Elektro

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Skills: Project Management, Fullstack Development, Web Design, Query, Mobile Development
- Programming Languages: PHP, Javascript, Typescript, Flutter (Dart), Python
- Development Practices: Agile Scrum
- Tools: Git, Jira, Trello
- · Languages: Indonesia, English

REFERENCES

Alexander Horizon Nafies Kamaluddien

Engineer Manager Tech. Lead

+62812-8183-7477 +62856-9333-8168